BETHANY LINDBERG

Location: McKinney, TX 75071 | **Phone:** 309-839-6852 | **Email:** bethanyllindberg@gmail.com **LinkedIn:** linkedin.com/in/bethany-lindberg-930155127

SUMMARY

Strong logical and analytical thinker with supply chain and statistical training and passion for data analysis and visualization. Quick learner with demonstrated time management and organizational skills with ability to prioritize to meet deadlines. Background in private sector as well as public sector analysis roles, including focus on Ecommerce, distribution, manufacturing and contract implementation/management. Extensive experience with working cross-functionally within both small and large organizations and with external vendors and customers.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Applications: Salesforce, Tableau, Bonfire

Programming Languages: VBA, Python, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Software: Windows Suite with Advanced Excel, NetSuite ERP, Quickbooks Enterprise

Databases: SQL, NoSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant - Data Science Bootcamp Southern Methodist University

08/2019 - Present Dallas, TX

- Follow detailed lesson plans and assist instructor in class time management. Track attendance, remote attendance requests and grade and provide feedback for student homework assignments and projects.
- Support students individually and in groups as they learn the following technical skills: Python, Pandas, Matplotlib, NumPy, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, D3, Leaflet, SQL, noSQL, Tableau, Machine Learning and Hadoop.

Buyer III City of Dallas Office of Procurement Services

01/2018 - 02/2019

Dallas, TX

- Coordinate, prepare and execute the procurement of goods and services under minimal supervision to ensure goods and services are obtained at minimal cost, best quality, maximum value, in a fair competitive market with internal contacts. Making decisions in compliance with Federal, State and City guidelines and policies.
- Provide written justification for purchasing decision along with detailed description of procurement process. Assemble exhaustive backup documentation to justify recommended vendor and price for review by management and City councilmembers if requested.
- Evaluate vendor qualifications, analyze RFX pricing and provide recommendations based on examining criteria such as price, quality, features, delivery and service schedules, etc.
- Interface with managers, coordinators, directors and vendors on project timeline and key target dates to meet deadlines.
- Monitor the spend on over 60 contracts utilized by multiple departments. Review department spend reports by commodity or agreement to determine potential cost savings.
- Project management for the processing of multi-year/multi-million-dollar agreements including contract execution, contract extensions and change orders for goods and services under minimal supervision. Coordinate negotiation of contract terms and pricing between multiple City departments and vendors.

Key Accomplishments:

- Chosen to represent City at Bonfire user conference based on ability to analyze data
- Replaced multiple long expired contracts using cross-functional organization

Purchasing and Logistics Assistant Sourcingpartner, Inc.

05/2017 - 12/2017 McKinney, TX

- Create daily purchase orders and monitor open purchase orders along with open sales orders to fill customer orders before due date.
- Curate and maintain detailed records of purchases along with justification for each purchase order and resulting revenue and profit.
- Review imports for compliance and fulfill all documentation requirements.

• Organize large amounts of data for ease of use by multiple departments and create BI dashboard with key data points for executive review.

Key Accomplishments:

- Improved KPIs by 75% by developing open order reports for 4 eCommerce platforms
- Reduced Excess Inventory by over 50% with data analysis in Excel by increasing sales and returning slow moving items
- Increased profit margin of non-stock program from 15% to 24% by lowering costs with strategic sourcing
- Decreased time required for weekly processes by up to 100% with custom NetSuite report and Excel array formula

Customer Service/Inventory Control Inner Pack, Inc

08/2014 - 4/2017 Fort Wayne, IN

- Maintain accurate inventory reports, investigate inventory discrepancies and implement root cause analysis and correction.
- Sales support duties including sourcing, procurement, quoting/estimating and vendor and customer management.
- Plan, schedule and supervise warehouse to ensure manufacturing jobs and distribution deliveries completed before promised due date.
- Implement and execute Vendor Managed Inventory program for key customer.

Key Accomplishments:

- Decreased inventory valuation to target level by analyzing historical data and setting reorder points to optimum levels and sourcing lower cost inventory where possible
- Increased productivity and accuracy of customer estimates and warehouse production orders by automating processes with Excel/VBA
- Achieved 10% cost savings to a large customer when requested by analyzing all the available data for areas with cost savings potential
- Discovered and negotiated with new vendors to solve sourcing deficiencies

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATION

Data Science Certificate: Southern Methodist University, Dallas, TX BA Liberal Arts: Thomas Edison State University, Trenton, NJ

Certified Supply Chain Specialist: IIMPR#74831

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Event Organizer/Presenter: Hack my Life Meetup - Transitioning to a Career in Data Science

Teaching Assistant - Introduction to Computer Science: Microsoft Teals